<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oidc on SoByte</title>
    <link>https://www.sobyte.net/tags/oidc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oidc on SoByte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 12:19:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sobyte.net/tags/oidc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OIDC (OpenID Connect) Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-07/oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 12:19:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-07/oidc/</guid>
      <description>I recently learned about OIDC in the authentication system and put together a blog that covers the concepts, processes, and usage of OIDC. Before introducing these, we need to clarify two terms Authorization and Authentication.
Authorization vs Authentication Here is OKTA&amp;rsquo;s definition of the two terms.
Authentication, in the form of a key. The lock on the door only grants access to someone with the correct key in much the same way that a system only grants access to users who have the correct credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand the OIDC protocol and authentication mechanism</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-04/oidc-protocol-and-authentication-mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 10:13:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-04/oidc-protocol-and-authentication-mechanism/</guid>
      <description>When there are more and more Internet applications, each application implements its own identity storage, authentication and authorization, users need to register and login repeatedly on the application, which is a bad experience, and user identity information cannot be shared and synchronized among multiple applications. When using enterprise applications, companies provide a series of applications and have to switch between registration and login despite being operated by the same user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OIDC protocol and its use in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-03/kubernetes-oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 13:29:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-03/kubernetes-oidc/</guid>
      <description>Most of the authentication mechanisms in K8s are done with ServiceAccount. Although K8s has the concept of User, there is no resource that corresponds to a &amp;ldquo;person&amp;rdquo;, so it is still very difficult to do user management in K8s. The good thing is that K8s provides an alternative way for user management, which is to interface with the OIDC protocol. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at what the OIDC protocol is and how it is used in K8s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
