<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kubectl on SoByte</title>
    <link>https://www.sobyte.net/tags/kubectl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kubectl on SoByte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 18:54:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sobyte.net/tags/kubectl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Develop and release a Kubectl plugin using Go</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-04/go-kubectl-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 18:54:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-04/go-kubectl-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Preface Under the ten-year cloud computing wave, DevOps, containers, microservices and other technologies are developing rapidly, and cloud-native has become a trend. Enterprises are moving from &amp;ldquo;ON Cloud&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;IN Cloud&amp;rdquo; and becoming &amp;ldquo;new cloud-native enterprises&amp;rdquo;, where new capabilities and existing capabilities are established but not broken, with organic synergy to achieve Resource efficiency, application agility, business intelligence, security and trustworthiness. The whole concept of cloud-native is very big, and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically archiving argo workflow logs using kubectl</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-03/archive-argo-workflow-log-by-kubectl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 09:46:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-03/archive-argo-workflow-log-by-kubectl/</guid>
      <description>The project uses argo-workflow as the workflow engine to orchestrate and run some hyperconverged cluster deployment related tasks, and the whole environment runs on a single node K3s. The main reason for choosing argo-workflow + K3s is to consume as few system resources as possible, since this environment will run on various laptops with different hardware configurations in the future 😂. After researching some common K8s deployment tools, we finally chose K3s, which consumes less system resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
