<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>victoriametrics on SoByte</title>
    <link>https://www.sobyte.net/tags/victoriametrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in victoriametrics on SoByte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 17:17:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sobyte.net/tags/victoriametrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VictoriaMetrics Source Code Analysis - Bloom Filter</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-05/victoriametrics-bloomfilter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 17:17:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-05/victoriametrics-bloomfilter/</guid>
      <description>VictoriaMetrics&amp;rsquo; vmstorage component receives metrics passed upstream, and in real-world scenarios, the order of magnitude of metrics or transient metrics can be so horrific that if the size of the cache is not limited, there is a risk of excessive slow inserts due to cache misses.
For this purpose, vmstorage provides two parameters: maxHourlySeries and maxDailySeries, which are used to limit the unique series added to the cache per hour/day. uniqueSeries means a unique time series, such as metrics{label1=&amp;quot;value1&amp;quot;,label2=&amp;quot;value2&amp;quot;} belonging to a time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of VictoriaMetrics Clustering Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-05/victoriametrics-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 13:43:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-05/victoriametrics-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Earlier we described the use of the single-node version of VictoriaMetrics. For ingestion rates below one million data points per second, it is recommended that the single-node version be used instead of the clustered version. The single-node version scales with the number of CPU cores, RAM, and available storage space. The single-node version is easier to configure and operate than the clustered version, so think twice before using the clustered</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Long Term Remote Storage Solution VictoriaMetrics Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-04/victoriametrics-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 10:44:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-04/victoriametrics-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>VictoriaMetrics (VM) is a highly available, cost-effective and scalable monitoring solution and time series database for long-term remote storage of Prometheus monitoring data. Compared to Thanos, VictoriaMetrics is primarily a horizontally scalable local full-volume persistent storage solution, VictoriaMetrics is more than just a temporal database, its advantages are mainly reflected in the following points. External support for Prometheus-related APIs, which can be used directly in Grafana as a Prometheus data</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
