<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grafana on SoByte</title>
    <link>https://www.sobyte.net/tags/grafana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grafana on SoByte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 12:15:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sobyte.net/tags/grafana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Usage of Grafana Loki Query Language LogQL</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/logql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 12:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/logql/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by PromQL, Loki also has its own query language, called LogQL, which is like a distributed grep that aggregates views of logs. Like PromQL, LogQL is filtered using tags and operators, and has two main types of query functions.
 Query to return log line contents Calculating relevant metrics in the log stream by filtering rules  Log queries A basic log query consists of two parts.
 log stream selector log pipeline  Due to the design of Loki, all LogQL queries must contain a Log Stream selector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Grafana Loki-based Log Alerts</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/grafana-loki-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 23:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/grafana-loki-alert/</guid>
      <description>For a production environment and an aspiring ops person, even millisecond level downtime is not tolerated. Proper logging and monitoring of infrastructure and applications is very helpful in solving problems, and can also help optimize costs and resources, as well as help detect some problems that may occur later. Earlier we learned to use Prometheus for monitoring alerts, but if we use Loki to collect logs can alerts be made</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Grafana Loki with Read-Write Separation Patterns</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/grafana-loki-rw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 14:11:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/grafana-loki-rw/</guid>
      <description>Built from multiple microservice components that can run as a horizontally scalable distributed system, Loki is uniquely designed to compile the code of an entire distributed system into individual binaries or Docker images, with the behavior of the individual binaries controlled by the -target command line flag.
Standalone mode The simplest mode of operation is to set -target=all, which is the default way and does not need to be specified. This is the monolithic mode, which runs all of Loki&amp;rsquo;s microservice components in a single process in the form of a single binary or Docker image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor of Kubernetes Using Prometheus Grafana</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-03/monitor-of-kubernetes-using-prometheus-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 11:28:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-03/monitor-of-kubernetes-using-prometheus-grafana/</guid>
      <description>The Prometheus community is updating so fast that some of the documentation written before is a bit out of date. Recently, I started to focus on observability again, and make up for some knowledge points in operation and maintenance.
1. Explanation of terms  Grafana  A visualization tool that provides various visualization panels and supports various data sources, including Prometheus, OpenTSDB, MySQL, etc.
 Prometheus  A time series database, mainly used to collect, store, and provide query data to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excellent Grafana K8S Plugin - DevOpsProdigy KubeGraf</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-12/grafana-k8s-plugin-kubegraf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 14:45:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-12/grafana-k8s-plugin-kubegraf/</guid>
      <description>DevOpsProdigy KubeGraf is an excellent Grafana Kubernetes plugin, an update to Grafana&amp;rsquo;s official Kubernetes Plugin. The plugin can be used to visualize and analyze the performance of a Kubernetes cluster, visually displaying the metrics and characteristics of the main services of the Kubernetes cluster through various graphs, and can also be used to examine the application lifecycle and error logs. Environment Requirements To install and use the DevOpsProdigy KubeGraf plugin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Grafana Dashboard with Kubernetes Resource Objects</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-11/use-crd-create-grafana-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:33:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-11/use-crd-create-grafana-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>When we use Grafana Dashboard to display our monitoring charts, we often go to someone else&amp;rsquo;s Dashboard and change it, but this also causes many people using Grafana to have no idea how to customize a Dashboard, although it is not very difficult. Here we introduce a relatively new tool: DARK, full name Dashboards As Resources in Kubernetes., which means that through the Kubernetes resource object to define Grafana Dashboard,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grafana Loki Concise Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-10/grafana-loki-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 12:43:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-10/grafana-loki-usage/</guid>
      <description>Loki, the latest open source project from the Grafana Labs team, is a horizontally scalable, high-availability, multi-tenant log aggregation system. It is designed to be very cost effective and easy to use because it does not index log content, but rather configures a set of tags for each log stream. Project inspired by Prometheus , the official description is: Like Prometheus, but for logs , similar to the Prometheus logging</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grafana raises $220 million, grows valuation 10-fold in two years</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-08/grafana-labs-raises-220-million/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:16:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-08/grafana-labs-raises-220-million/</guid>
      <description>Grafana Labs, the developer of the well-known open source project Grafana, recently raised $220 million in Series C funding, which now values Grafana Labs at $3 billion, a tenfold increase from two years ago.
The round was co-led by Sequoia Capital and Coatue Management, with participation from existing investors Lightspeed Venture Partners, Lead Edge Capital and GIC. Sequoia Capital partner Carl Eschenbach, who previously served as president of VMware, will join Grafana&amp;rsquo;s board of directors through this investment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
