<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rtsp on SoByte</title>
    <link>https://www.sobyte.net/tags/rtsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rtsp on SoByte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 13:22:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sobyte.net/tags/rtsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implement a simple RTSP server</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-07/rtsp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 13:22:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-07/rtsp-server/</guid>
      <description>In the previous article, the RTSP protocol itself was briefly introduced, and this time we will talk about how to implement a simple RTSP server.
Live555 Live555 is a C++ media library that supports a wide range of media services protocols, streaming, receiving and processing audio and video data in a variety of audio and video encoding formats.
It is also one of the few available libraries, and its code is rather cumbersome, but it is simple enough for most people to get started with, so it is perfect for practice and rewriting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTSP Protocol Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-07/rtsp-explain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 13:02:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-07/rtsp-explain/</guid>
      <description>When we talk about RTSP, it is actually not only the RTSP protocol itself, but we will actually inevitably talk about the following protocols.
RTP (Real-time Transport Protocol): the protocol really used to transmit audio-video, generally based on the UDP protocol, with special attention to the fact that it uses an even number of ports. RTCP (Real-time Control Protocol): sister protocol to RTP, which provides quality of service (QoS) feedback by periodically sending statistical information, it uses an odd number of ports and is RTP port + 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
