<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ebpf on SoByte</title>
    <link>https://www.sobyte.net/tags/ebpf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ebpf on SoByte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 12:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sobyte.net/tags/ebpf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why is eBPF so popular?</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/ebpf-popular/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 12:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/ebpf-popular/</guid>
      <description>The eBPF is a register-based virtual machine originally designed to filter network packets, and is known as the Extended Berkeley Packet Filter (eBPF) since the original paper was written at the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. This paper will explain why eBPF is so popular in easy-to-understand language.
Introduction to eBPF In layman&amp;rsquo;s terms, eBPF is a custom program that runs in the kernel of the operating system when triggered by an event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-depth understanding of eBPF｜7 core issues you need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/ebpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 12:41:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-06/ebpf/</guid>
      <description>Over the past year, ARMS has built Kubernetes monitoring based on eBPF technology, providing multi-language non-intrusive application performance, system performance, and network performance observation capabilities, validating the effectiveness of eBPF technology. eBPF technology and ecology are developing well, and the future prospects are vast. As a practitioner of this technology, the goal of this paper is to introduce eBPF technology by answering 7 core questions itself, to unravel the eBPF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking rpcx microservices with ebpf</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-05/ebpf-to-trace-rpcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 13:08:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2022-05/ebpf-to-trace-rpcx/</guid>
      <description>ebpf is an innovative and revolutionary technology that enables sandboxed programs to be run in the kernel without modifying the kernel source code or loading kernel modules. By making the Linux kernel programmable, it is possible to build smarter, more feature-rich infrastructure software based on existing (rather than adding new) abstraction layers, without increasing system complexity or sacrificing execution efficiency or security. The first version of BPF was introduced in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Foundation Welcomes New &#34;Member&#34;, eBPF Foundation Formed</title>
      <link>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-08/new-member-ebpf-foundation-formed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 16:57:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sobyte.net/post/2021-08/new-member-ebpf-foundation-formed/</guid>
      <description>On August 12, 2021 EST, Google, Microsoft, Isovalent, Facebook, and Netflix jointly announced the formation of a new non-profit organization, the eBPF Foundation, under the auspices of the Linux Foundation. The Foundation is dedicated to better promoting the open source project eBPF and supporting the commercial growth of Linux and other open source technologies.
In recent years, the number of eBPF projects has exploded and more and more projects are interested in using eBPF, so it is increasingly important to optimize collaboration between projects, ensure that the core of eBPF is well maintained and configure a clear roadmap for the future of eBPF.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
